Bitcoin is on sale. The media will tell
you that it's crashing. I will tell you
that we are entering a new bull market
and it's probably time to buy the dip.
But meanwhile, Wall Street is picking
very specific altcoins next. Of course,
we're talking about the ETFs that are
coming and a report from Citrini
Research. We are going to talk about all
of that and more with everybody's
favorite guest, Matt Hogan from Bitwise.
Let's go.
That's dope.
>> That's dope.
>> Good morning everybody. Happy Friday and
welcome to the show. I'm gonna go ahead
and just bring on Matt now. Good
morning, sir. How are you?
>> I'm doing great. How are you?
>> I am doing
>> great. How are you?
>> Wonderfully well. So, uh, yeah. So,
we've got, uh, the death of Bitcoin
again, uh, to celebrate, which is always
good when I have you on the show. Uh,
but now, here we go. Crypto Well, we got
to share it, don't we? Crypto crumbles
as anniversary of flash crash near. So,
yeah, I guess we actually should be
having PTSD tomorrow
uh, for the year anniversary of the 19.2
two billion dollar liquidation event
that I think it's actually kind of crazy
to me that we still don't really know
what happened that day by the way. Do
you?
>> Yeah,
>> maybe you know
>> the details. Yeah.
>> Um I mean that was a crazy day. I think
I think three or four or five different
things happened. You had the peg stable
coin, you had a a macro crash, you had
them all come together at once. Um, so
still is pretty crazy, but it's also
crazy that uh the media is willing to to
to kill the the Bitcoin bull market
after three months and say that we're
over because we pulled back a few
percent.
>> Yeah, I would like to just present you
with a chart because I happen to be
looking at it and I looked at this. This
is the Bitcoin chart. This is exactly
where the bull bare market technically
ends for chart people, right? because
you made a higher high and price is
literally just sitting exactly right
there which is if you are a technical
analyst
all you want to see is levels that were
sitting there for years or months to be
broken being broken and tested as
support but here we are at the end that
that to me is like just from a technical
perspective is the most gratuitous buy
>> I'm not even a technician uh but even to
me that looks exceptionally good uh I
completely agree yeah and certainly yeah
certainly not dead I Yeah, I woke up
this morning. It's at 82 something.
Great. Onward.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, let's talk about uh I
guess we could talk about ETF flows in
and out as as exhausting as it is, but I
think on Wednesday we had a pretty
massive outflow day, right? Like a half
a billion day. And it was relatively
spread across everything. It wasn't one
of those uh it's because of Black Rockck
Options days, right? So, uh but that was
after we have had historic inflows just
weeks before, right? So, I mean, is it
even worth watching these on a
day-to-day basis, honestly, or is it
totally just, you know, tracking price
or leading? I don't, you know,
>> yeah, I mostly think it's following
price on a day-to-day basis. It it
follows nuances in the options. When you
see that across the curve move on a
single day, uh there's usually something
funky going on on the other side. It's
hard to say exactly what that funky
thing is on the other side. If you see
sustained large outflows over multiple
days, you and I have talked about this,
but the actual reporting onto an
individual day is a little bit uh
variant. You really should look at these
on fiveday flows uh to get a feel for
what's going on. To be sure, we've had a
few days of outflows across the whole
ecosystem, across Bitcoin, particularly
across ETH, across some other assets. So
there has been a cool down of investor
flows, but I would describe it as that a
little cool down after some really
strong inflows. And I think we'll be
we'll be back to the inflow trend before
long.
>> I agree. And so this is one of the lead
stories here. JP Morgan estimates 50
billion is flowed into crypto this year
as momentum improves into Q4. I think
they put it at, you know, annualized.
They think it'd be 65 billion or so.
That's a much more compelling statement
than what ETFs did on a daily or weekly
or even monthly basis at this point.
First of all, do you think that's an
accurate number and you know where's
that flowing?
>> Yeah, I thought that was a great a great
article uh and a great note from JP
Morgan. I mean, they were combining ETF
flows and implied derivative flows and
corporate purchases. They were really
looking at institutional capital moving
into crypto. And I think a lot of the
media thinks it only moves in via ETFs.
Obviously, as an ETF issuer, I wish that
were true, but in fact, it moves in
through ETFs, through corporate
purchases, through derivatives exposure,
and JP Morgan was aggregating that up. I
think the most important chart in that
article, if you panned down, you would
see the flows sort of yearbyear.
And what you want to do is compare 2026
over 2022. And what you can see is uh
while the flows have come down from sort
of the the the glory days of ETF
launching, they're up significantly
cycle over cycle. And to me, that's the
real important point. Like you really
have to compare where we are now versus
where we were in the last cycle. And you
could see that on that basis we're 2 3
4x. It's a much more institutional
market. And to me, that was the big
takeaway of that report.
>> Yeah. And also like if we're actually
entering a crypto cycle, which you know,
as you know, I would didn't think was a
thing until now, I think it's probably a
thing. Um, you know, the whole topping
in October and then having a bare market
thing may have convinced me that I was
wrong. But, uh, you know, what do you
know what then 2027 2028 look like,
right? We see the down through the what
would be the, uh, kind of, you know,
four year cycle and then right back up,
I would imagine, in the coming years.
So,
>> yeah. And and I'll just tell you
anecdotally on the road. I've spent much
of the last month going to conferences,
large wealth conferences, wirehouse
conferences, and I will say the the the
attitude has really shifted. Uh Bitcoin
has become uh really mainstream, right?
You're no longer looked at in any way
like the guy with horns on your head. I
mean, you have Morgan Stanley launching
ETFs. You have Wells Fargo putting
Bitcoin into models. I suspect that that
2024 number will be eclipsed during this
cycle pretty significantly in terms of
inflows. I've never felt sort of the the
normalized feeling of Bitcoin as I have
over the last month at these wealth
platforms.
>> Yeah, I even feel that anecdotally like
with friends, family, and other people.
I think maybe crypto or you know they're
certainly not they're certainly not like
uh asking me about hyperlquid,
>> right? point and Bitcoin I think is
definitely just a part of the mainstream
conversation and I think it's for a long
time.
>> Yeah. But it's really remarkable. I mean
the other day Black Rockck put out a
note about AI agents using Bitcoin as a
store of value and no one blinked,
right? I mean that would have been like
a fantasy dream. Think of that in 2022.
Think of that in 2018. It'd be
completely absurd. You would get excited
if they muttered the word Bitcoin, even
if it was followed by something like is
a worthless technological experiment.
You'd be like, "At least they said it."
Um, and now they're talking about AI
agents saving in Bitcoin. Uh, it's it's
really it's crazy.
>> I I totally agree. It's just the
normalization even. I don't think I
could have imagined it. I don't think
that means everybody owns it. I think a
lot of them will come around to it, but
there's just like you said, just nobody
nobody thinks I'm like the crazy Bitcoin
guy anymore.
>> Now I'm just we're only as weird as like
gold bugs or like Tesla fanatics now.
>> That's that that's that's about right.
That's the
>> company
normal. Uh thinking speaking of things
that are absurd, by the way, before we
move on specifically to you know what
Bitwise is doing, the near ETF and a lot
of other topics that I want to talk
about if people were wondering what the
narrative is for yesterday's Bitcoin
crash back to levels not seen since like
days ago, but uh it was OpenAI projected
to bring in 20 billion less in revenue
than expected. I don't know if people
saw this story, but man, it's hilarious
because it's literally somebody
basically leaked what they thought the
revenue would be and then they leaked
what the revenue actually is and it's
just an accounting error and people are
like OpenAI is finished. They're over.
They're making $20 billion left. But
like it says here, Enthropic reportedly
includes sales made through cloud
partners such as AWS and Google Cloud,
while OpenAI does not include comparable
partner sales in the same way. So it's
literally an accounting mistake that
apparently can now crash global markets
in a day. And it's because they're
basically saying we're reporting our net
potential revenue instead of gross
potential revenue or something like
>> it is really remarkable. I think it
speaks to something which is this uh
this existential dread that many people
feel about the AI boom like they feel
like at any moment to like pull the
Charles Prince uh metaphor from 2008
back at any moment the the music will
stop and you'll find out whether you
have a chair or not. I mean we have Ray
Dallio saying the end of the bubble is
near and then you ask him why and he's
like I think it is. Um, so it's
it's it's this weird like it's, you
know, people are obviously pattern
matching the growth of AI to previous
major infrastructure builds and
therefore they're assuming that it's
going to end. There's so much worry
about it that even a misreported uh sort
of accounting uh quirk can send the
market spiraling. So it it does say
something about the market. everyone's
wondering. They they all know or think
they know that at some point the music
will end and um and so they're they're
very much on on tent hooks uh with it. I
mean, I get it. I guess to some degree
because it is the whole market at this
point seemingly and we were I was
talking about this the other day with
Noel Aerson. Actually, I have a Peter
Schiff interview coming out this weekend
which was surprisingly measured in
normal by the way. Uh but uh because we
didn't talk about Bitcoin, but you know,
but he he pointed out that if you
actually look at the like the breadth of
the stock market that half the stock
market's in a bare market if you're
looking at individual names, right? And
it's all I guess before it was buoyed by
the Mag 7. Now it's sort of like AI or
chips or whatever the rotation is at the
moment. But I guess it's a reasonable
feeling to think that if the you know
five or 10 names that are supporting the
entire market roll over that be in bad
shape.
>> I think that's I think that's fair.
Although I think some of that
underperformance is those five or 10
names sucking capital out of the other
names more so than
>> Yeah. more so than than poor economic
performance or poor economic earnings. I
would guess if you looked at the overall
earnings of the S&P 500, they may tell a
different story than performance. We
felt that so acutely in crypto where AI
was sucking capital out of crypto for a
while and that definitely contributed to
the last bare market cycle. So I think
there's an element of that in it as
well. But of course, you have to be a
little bit worried about it. You have to
play the game in your head of what
happens if that crash happens. Uh as
crypto investors, we should ask what
happens if that crash happens. Um, I
think in the end it ends up uh with
Bitcoin doing exceptionally well. Uh,
but there might be a little hiccup in
the middle. Uh, but I see no signs that
we're rolling over, right? There's no
>> I'm back in the uh bad news is good for
crypto, good news is good for crypto
phase, which I, you know, I I'm
sometimes uncomfortable with, but you
know, we went up when everything else is
kind of breaking down. you know, gold's
breaking below uh key levels and while
Bitcoin is breaking above it, the stock
market, like I said, it's kind of all
over the place and Bitcoin's doing its
own thing as it tends to do in these
cycles. So, I think, you know, you've
got the debasement narrative could send
it. Uh if stocks continue up, that could
help it. I, you know, I'm just not in a
place where I'm particularly worried
about Bitcoin after it just finally
broke out.
>> Totally agree. I described it the other
day to someone as a choose your own
adventure novel where every choice leads
on the same page at the end which is
with Bitcoin's price higher.
>> I remember those novels when I was a kid
at all. I remember dying a lot in from
aliens
>> 100%.
>> Why don't we have those anymore?
>> I know it was a great format. It
>> was such a good format and I bet that
our audience actually has read those. So
yeah, I mean I I just think that uh
we're in a very good place right now. So
maybe you could talk about uh you know
moving into how you guys are positioning
for that. I mean we've got it kind of a
lot. We can talk about specifically the
AI space. There's very the very handsome
Hunter Horesley. Bitwise CEO Hunter
Horesley says AI and crypto are cut from
the same cloth and that it plans to do
more with AI. Bitwise has two pending AI
ETF applications. The Bitwise AI cyber
defense ETF and the Bitwise AI bond ETF.
It's also launched the first US spot
near ETF last week. So we could dive
into all of that, but this is feels like
a nice little expansion that some of
these are just AI without the crypto
side in them and then you obviously have
the AI crypto and then you have all the
crypto. So you're pretty much covered on
all the bases there.
>> Yeah, I mean obviously I can't speak too
much about filings that are in the
water, but uh there are a lot of things
in the AI space that are extraordinarily
adjacent uh to crypto. We've been as an
industry at the forefront of sort of
cyber attacks, right? and all the hacks
that we've been having I think are
directly attributable to what's been
going on in the AI space. If you're
operating a crypto company, you need to
be a deep expert or have a deep
expertise on your team about uh cyber
security and other things. So some of
these are sort of natural adjacencies uh
to what we're doing. And then on near
specifically that sort of follows the
bitwise pattern of looking down the
stack and trying to find assets that we
think have very significant upside if
things play out in a particular way. Uh
I'm hugely bullish on near uh sort of at
two tiers of what it could become. One
as a standalone blockchain, two is a
play on AI. Yeah, there was there was my
article. The point I was making in this
article which is what I I really love
near uh as a as an interesting
investment is that if you buy near you
get something already that works. You
get intense which the revenue on tense
and the usage on intense is ramping
extraordinarily quickly. And then almost
for free, you get this optionality of
one of the sort of original authors of
the paper that kicked off the LLM boom
trying to build the central place where
AI agents will operate. The the
criticism of NAR is that when you look
under the surface, it says it's the
blockchain for AI, but it's mostly used
by humans. And so people are like,
they're not doing what they say. But to
me,
>> doing what I mean, AI agents aren't
doing what we say yet.
>> Exactly. That's the whole point. Yeah,
that's the whole point. If you're
waiting for a multi-t trillion dollar AI
agent economy, we're just not there yet.
Uh that doesn't mean you can't build
something that will serve that. And if
you build something that will serve
that, but it has an existing business
that is awesome, uh it's a pretty
interesting investment. So, um yeah, we
were excited to bring NRR to market and
the response has been great. You know,
we we've have uh tens of millions of
dollars flow in. I think it'll be
hundreds of millions soon. Um, I think
it's a great project.
>> It's interesting. I I've been working on
a book idea and one of the examples is
how ne a lot of people think that
Netflix became so massively successful
by going all in on streaming, but
actually it was like a very side test
business while they were still sending
out red envelopes for years, right? And
so I think the perception in hindsight,
but that's exactly this, right? they
have a very successful business and then
they can actually you can take a bet uh
that it becomes what they say it could
become also on the side which is very
much how Netflix became Netflix.
>> I love that example. That's exactly
right. These are my favorite
investments. I feel this way about
Bitcoin for what it's worth. I think
it's a store of value and I think that's
an established market and I think you
get an optionality premium that it could
one day be used for international
commerce and if that happens that's like
another catalyst on top of it. So,
anytime you can get a free moonshot,
uh, I think that's pretty cool. I think
Netflix is a great example. I think Near
is a great example.
>> If we need a multi- trillion dollar
agentic economy before people decide
that it's a real thing and invest, you
will be the one buying the top of that
bubble that we were talking about.
>> That's exactly right. Yes. Exactly
right.
>> Right. Because at that point, it'll be
commoditized. There'll be hundreds of
ways to invest in it. people will be
piling in late like they we've seen in
crypto for years and you know building
the hyperlquid of X and all those things
fail or the like the 15th gaming token
and that'll be
>> and there's nothing to do. Yeah, that's
exactly right. But it's always hard to
invest in those things that aren't here
yet because if it has no traction then
you're it's really speculative. I just
love that it has traction and a useful
tool. You know, a year ago, a year ago,
I would have said like uh it was a
really speculative bet, but now
everybody's already using Grockbot and
Muse and Dot from Chat GBT. I think for
the first time in the last month or two,
everybody can actually feel what an
agent can do from you more than in
theory.
>> Like it's sending your emails now and
giving you alerts when like your kids
need you and stuff. I mean, real things
are happening with these agents and
every I was saying this actually to my
wife uh yesterday. I was like three
months or four six months ago maybe
whatever we we set up open claw in my
office right and we got a computer over
here and we didn't want to give it
anything
like you had the stories about the
Facebook lady accidentally emailing the
entire company and like you know these
things going out in the wild
>> and we're already at the point where now
I think your average person like signs
on to Grockpot it's like attach your
email like cool
>> dingle
drive in your entire life ding Right.
And so it's like that moment. I remember
when nobody would put their credit card
in the internet.
>> Right. Exactly.
>> And then all of a sudden one day it was
like, I guess we could, you know, https
or whatever. It's perfectly fine to put
my credit card on the internet. And I
think we're there now, which means the
money side is going to be here in
months.
>> It's going to be here in months. I mean,
what is the number one conversation at
Thanksgiving going to be? It's going to
be about Muse. It's going to be about
Crockbot. It's going to be like, let me
show you how you can save money on your
subscriptions that you haven't canceled.
Uh, so I think it's going to accelerate
really quickly.
>> I agree. So, uh, just to put this in
context from, uh, your your buddy Teddy,
I didn't realize Teddy was a penguin.
It's awesome.
>> He got his own penguin PFP. I mean, that
guy's a legend.
>> Him, right? Uh, of 107, which I thought
abstract uh, closing down, by the way, I
thought was kind of sad. But, uh, of 107
US ETFs launched in September, NRR was
top 10 in AOM gathered. It launched on
the penultimate business day of the
month. up against monsters from State
Street, Black Rockck, Tro, etc. The
largest asset managers in the world.
Incredible community strength. So, this
wasn't like
just a small drop in the bucket
theoretical attempt. This thing has done
actually exceptionally well.
>> It's done exceptionally well. Uh there
is a strong community. I mean, that's a
remarkable fact.
>> Is that who buys it? I mean, I I think I
asked Hunter that, but is it like their
strong community that comes in and buys
it? Right.
>> Usually the ETFs are like a a two hump
inflow story when they launch. When you
first launch, the first people who buy
it is the community or people who are
already familiar. No financial advisor
sees a press release and then smashes by
for $10 million. That's not what
happens. So you get this community hump
and then later on as the sales team does
its work and as media does it work and
people learn about it you get this
second hump of sort of uh later adopters
and so the initial bump is people who
are already excited about Near and uh
there were a lot of them um you know I
will say I shared this story in
uh in in my article on it that there is
institutional interest institutions
always ask me what what sort of moonshot
crypto projects are interesting to by
and near is one of the examples that I
give. So I think there'll be this second
hump, but that first hump is uh is
primarily communitydriven.
>> I I that's one of the few tokens I'm
very happy that I held through the
cycles even though I'm probably
marginally up, you know, rounding era.
I'm like I'm like strategy with their
Bitcoin right on any given day. It's
like he's got up on his near position or
down that he's holding for but I've it's
one of the few things that not only did
I hold but that I've bought more of and
every time I talk to you guys or I talk
to the team at near or you know I I was
joking I think everybody's at token 2049
I think I said this to Hunter but I
think he's there as well and he might be
going to his dinner but the I my friend
Chris uh runs all the marketing at near
and he used to be at Bullish and he was
at the TAI and I've just known him for
years. He was a New York City club guy
and he was like, "Hey, would you want to
come to this dinner?" I was like,
"Sadly, I'm not coming to Singapore."
And he's like, "Well, you know, I think
it was Hunter. I'll be there." He's
like, "Pology will be there. I think
twins will be there." And like as he
listed all these people coming to like a
near dinner. First of all, it was all
the people that like have
>> been behind this massive Zcash move,
>> right?
>> Right. Clear like whatever. I was like,
"Maybe I need to own more Near any
information like it's a public. I'm not,
you know, it's just like I was like,
"Wow, it seems like a lot of the people
that I very deeply respect in this
industry are very serious about this
thing."
>> Yeah, I think that's a good that's a
good insight. I love that story. That's
a great story. And I think that's right.
Right. It's like investing in a high
quality startup uh with interesting
founders that goes through periods of
product market fit and periods of
challenge. I mean, I like that you've
been invested for multiple years. It
really feels like watching a high
quality startup build that just happened
to has a liquid ticker attached to it.
Um yeah, where the smart people are
going to dinner is is not a bad
investment theory.
>> Yeah, it's you know you don't have much
to operate on in this space. If
if a meal is it then we got it. But
still listen like you're not the only
ones obviously talking about this
crossover between AI and crypto. First
of all, it's been one of I think the
most compelling narratives generally,
but a lot of people that you wouldn't
even anticipate necessarily uh starting
to talk about it or starting to talk
about it. So, Wall Street's tokenization
boom could have bigger winners than
Bitcoin and Ether, Catrini says. So, I
had never heard of Catrini until last
year when they had that one thing go
wildly viral and then I think they sent
a guy into the Straits of Hormuz to like
do his own research.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. So, uh but uh you know to my
knowledge I had never heard them or seen
them doing research on crypto. Maybe I'm
completely wrong but here Research
publishes article on intersection
between Aenta and crypto alongside their
investment basket. Right. So, I mean,
they literally like not only did they
say, "Hey, this thing's gonna happen,
they literally like did a
percentagebased portfolio of ways to
gain exposure to the AI and crypto
crossover." And I have seen,
>> once again, anecdotally, a lot of people
>> in my friend group who are Wall Street
sent me this this morning.
>> 100%. Yeah, this was
>> this is breaking through the wall. Like,
Catrini,
>> Catrini is definitely breaking through
the wall. I guess the financial
equivalent of going to the straight of
Hormuz is dying into diving into the
DeFi market. Um, but I, you know, I do
think
>> less or more minds, I don't know.
>> Exactly. No, but I I think this one uh
this one did cross the chasm. It did
reach real institutional distribution.
And that's a great list of projects. For
what it's worth, if you went into the
Bitwise research layer and asked what
sort of none crypto assets we're talking
about, uh, it would start at derive and
it would go down through lighter and it
would move through that sort of phase of
assets that they were calling out there.
It really felt like the Catrini analyst
uh hadn't seen what has happened in the
DeFi market for the last three or four
years and remembered it as sort of this
uh play area for NFTTS and then walked
in and found a fully functioning
financial market that operates 24/7 365
with serious projects providing sort of
every sort of financial utility. and the
the scales fell from his eyes and he saw
the future of finance. That's what it
felt like and that's actually what is
happening in DeFi, right? What you can
do in DeFi today is extraordinarily
robust. It works better than the
traditional system. It's getting easy to
use and it's backed by these projects
which are real projects providing real
utility. Um, I think it says a lot about
the space. Among other things, it says
that we're finally expanding from like
three tokens to 50 that Wall Street
believes in. That's the birth of an
asset class. Um, and I I think it's I
think it's actually an important moment
in the market.
>> Yeah. I I just can imagine like my
friends or the people at their offices
being like, "How do I get this backpack,
>> right?
>> Where do I get this aerodyome thing?
Like what's the dock ticker?" It's it's
a whole new it's a whole new world,
right? It's a whole new world for these
people. And some of those are very small
subbillion dollar assets. Uh I mean
that's the other important thing maybe
for people to realize is how early it
is, right? Many of those uh protocols
that Catrini is pointing to are measured
as sort of micro caps in an equity
equivalent and they're pointing to them
as sort of the leading provider of X. Uh
I think that's I think that's super
interesting and super exciting. I think
when we talked not that long ago, you
actually I think h so it wasn't last
time but hyperlquid you had just
released that which has been obviously
wildly successful as well and you kind
of alluded to the fact that maybe the
single asset ETF days were coming close
to an end, right? You you didn't say
this will be our last one by any
stretch, but NERA obviously has come. I
mean, how do you feel about that now?
Especially like you see this list is
this like everybody rushes to create an
ETF for every single thing on that list
because mentioned it ETF you know.
>> Yeah. Exact exactly. I think increas I
think we're close to the point where
what people want is the catrini
portfolio.
>> So
>> the the whole thing right because um the
reason single assets have dominated ETFs
is because the initial market is sort of
crypto experts who have very specific
views. I like Salana but not Ethereum. I
like Ethereum but not Salana. Uh I love
this asset, I hate this asset. And then
when you put them into a package, that
initial buying audience, remember sort
of that two hump distribution, um can't
stomach it because they don't like one
or two assets in it. But if you're
making a play on like a whole new
financial ecosystem, you don't just want
to own the options uh uh structure in
that space, right? That's not the bet
you're making is just to own derive
because options are just like a tiny
part of the financial stack. What you
want to own is the whole thing. Um,
right? You want to own the whole space.
So, I do think we're getting to the
point where we're going to start to see
basket based exposure. Something like
that basket I think would do very well
as an ETF.
>> Yeah. I Why haven't we seen that yet?
You and I have been talking about that
for three years.
>> Well, I should get to work. Um,
>> I blame you.
>> It is my fault. Yeah, I've been slacking
off. No, the reality is, you know, as a
as an ETF issuer, you look at the
existing index products, which I love
and I own our index product and I like
the hasht product and I think they're
great products
>> and those are actually very successful.
I mean, Hunter did point that out to me
last Sunday. He was like, "Our most
popular products are actually
>> now, just just now, right? Just now
those are really resonating with
people." So I do think I do think we're
getting close, but you have to go
through the cycle. You have to go single
asset to multi-asset to active, right?
Eventually in in a year and a half,
we'll be talking about the rise of
active crypto strategies will be my
guess. Um it sort of has to follow that
pattern.
>> And will they be driven by AI?
>> Of course, man. I I have to imagine that
like the next, you know, if you want to
get attention, you'll have to say that
this actively managed portfolio is
managed by some superior AI, you know,
and not by some human or at least.
>> That's right. Yeah. Super intelligence,
I think we're supposed to call it now.
>> AI.
>> Yes. But I think that's right. I think
that's right. But that's the pattern.
Single asset, multiasset, active. Um,
and I think we'll get there. I think
we're we're sort of crossing into
multi-asset now.
we we have this conversation a lot, but
now that we can finally say maybe we
consensus is that we could be moving
into a new bull market, right? And that
uh maybe we're actually seeing this
regime change that uh you know been
projecting here for a long time. What do
you think the altcoin market will look
like? I I've I my opinion may literally
change today by seeing Catrini talking
about these this thing because I thought
it would be probably really really
hyperfocused on a few assets. Now maybe
I think it could spread a little further
than that but I mean how do you see it
happening because obviously you guys
will be paying close attention to decide
what kind of products to launch.
>> Yeah I think it's going to be relatively
widespread in terms of the number of
assets but I think it's going to be
differentiated by which I mean I think
they're going to be winners and losers
in this space. Um I don't think people
are just going to smash by every
project. I don't think we'll get to this
until the very end. We'll get to the uh
sort of energy that we've had in
previous cryptoblow markets where the
goal is to pick the most absurd project
uh because that would go up the most. Uh
you know, people buying Etherox or
whatever. Um I'm not sure we'll get to
that sort of level. Uh uh but I do think
it's going to be relatively widespread.
There are a number of great projects out
there, right? When I look at the top 50,
I think I could find 20 to 25 projects
that I think are pretty interesting and
have a real shot on goal. So, I think
it'll be that kind of market, like half
on, half off. Um, and hopefully some of
the zombie projects will die. I would
love to see that happen as well.
>> Do you have an ether rock?
>> I do not. I do not. Do you?
>> No, I don't. Every I didn't I didn't
even think about there was a moment five
minutes
>> where I was like maybe I'll buy land in
the metaverse
>> of of course everyone had that thought.
Yeah.
>> And then uh I woke up. I was like that
was a horrible nightmare.
>> The Snoop doing it. I want to live next
to Snoop in the fake world of of
infinite land to be printed.
>> That you know like we we were like not
we but we the grander we were so stupid.
I mean people will go back and look at
>> like the 21 22 like aliens will come
back and study that.
>> Yes.
>> That's like that was wild. I mean the
things that people were like deeply
convinced were you know the the like uh
Bieber buying board ape phase
>> whole business I remember there was a
whole business that basically's job was
to like place board apes in the hands of
celebrities for like a 20% vig on 10x
over market value apes.
>> Completely wild. I mean that was a
completely completely wild uh period but
it was it was broad. I mean you speak of
you know like buying land in the
metaverse but Facebook changed its name.
Um you know there were there were
serious people making serious bets in
that space. Uh but yeah there's
obviously a lot of insanity. Uh
>> I think Facebook should change their
name back.
>> They're going to change it to Muse. Um
you know just give just give them a
little bit of time. Uh yeah, I don't
know. Uh but that that was a that was a
crazy period. And it's also a reminder
of how early we are. You know, we're
talking about being a new bull market
cycle. There's none of that energy,
right? We're not anywhere close to that
energy. People are looking for real
projects. They're demanding revenue. It
is a completely different environment
than we were in back then.
>> Yeah. There's no honestly I don't really
think there's any froth. Like I think
that every everything that's gone up has
a pretty good reason to have gone up and
people could see it going much higher
for those same reasons rather than
thinking I need to sell this thing. It's
it's all over.
>> Yeah, I think
>> I really think it's very different this
time.
>> I think it's very different this time.
The valuations are lower, the revenue is
might be we might be having in two years
it might be we might be talking about
the froth.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That'll be fun too uh
in a different way. But um yeah, I mean
that's the way this market goes, right?
when you have a highly uh cyclical
market, you get froth at the top, but
we're we're we're not anywhere near
there. Um it will worry me if we start
to see zombie coins sort of rally a new
and and and go up hundreds of percent.
Maybe that's a sign of a local top, but
uh but we're not anywhere near that now.
>> Okay. Well, you and I have to do
something that I wasn't sure I wanted to
do. There's two things I'm not sure I
want to do today. One of them is All in
Every Time. and Julia Garner and Anthony
Bole stars Carolyn Ellison and Sam
Bankfrieded in this limited series about
the love scores behind the FTX sandals.
So number one that I do want to do but
don't want to do is you we're going to
watch the trailer you you and I together
and then we're going to comment on I
want everybody to see this if they
missed it. And then the number two is
that I have Hunter Biden on my schedule
at one o'clock and I can't
but uh Okay,
>> what a one two. Oh my god.
>> Hey, let let's see who they cast. It's
the girl from Ozark. Like I her as
Carolyn Ellison said is blowing my mind.
But we're we're just going to watch it
because talk about like things from last
cycle coming back around here. Here we
go. You ready? Let's let's go everybody.
>> Hey, I'm Sam.
>> Caroline.
>> I'm going to give you a brain teaser.
You'll better percentage of your chips.
>> So, the game's about analyzing risk. All
in.
>> You could lose everything.
>> Going all in every time is the
mathematically optimal strategy.
>> That's her. That's the girl. She's
really cool. I always said that I am
going to make a difference.
>> I believe you.
>> What if we built our own cryptocurrency
business? We can call it FTX.
>> Do you know anything about crypto?
>> It's the wild west out there. Whoever
gets there first has the opportunity to
do some real good. A crypto fund that
earns to give. We are going to change
the world. And this campus and these
people are going to help us do that. You
and I are side by side all the way.
>> Oh.
>> Oh my god.
>> We aren't making a million dollars a
day.
>> If we reinvest all in every day, how can
we possibly lose?
>> You and Sam are the two smartest people
I've ever met. But sometimes I can't
fathom how you can both be so stupid.
>> All in.
>> We have a duty
>> to invest responsibly.
>> We couldn't lose everything.
>> We go all in. We're out.
Lying isn't bad for a good cause, but
what if the Wall Street Journal finds
out what you're hiding?
>> You were the one who did it. There's no
such thing as criminals. It's just
people who get caught.
>> Dude, you got to promise me you won't
say anything. Okay.
>> Sam and Caroline stole $8 billion from
customers.
>> What?
>> I up.
>> Agreed.
We're the good guys. Remember
>> I don't know who I can trust.
>> You trust me, right?
>> Wow. Wow. What's What's What's your
feeling watching that?
>> Well, first of all, it's uncanny how
much that looks like SPF and Caroline.
>> Spot on. Perfect casting.
>> I I can't imagine that any part of that
is accurate to how it went down. That
that's what like that's what I I can't
look at that and be like this is the
story.
>> Obviously not. Um it is brutal to watch
them and this this happened during it
like like like almost a whitewashing of
uh of of a Chinese book. Yeah.
>> Right. Um Yeah. Oh, this crazy sort of
weird guy made some mistakes. Um, is a
crazy way to view what happened there.
It's a little
>> I mean, I don't know if like where they
get the comment, if we just go all in
and double down every single day, we
can't lose money.
Can you imagine going to a roulette
table
>> and you win and you double down and you
win and you double down and you can't
ever lose. It's mathematically
impossible. There's no way that strategy
can go bad badly for you.
>> Actually, it's mathematically the
opposite thing. Um, uh, yeah, that's I
mean, that's that's that's really
remarkable. I guess I guess, you know,
I'm I'm supposed to be the optimist that
you bring on your show. Uh, that's
always bullish. So, the optimistic spin
is this this shows that we've healed
fully from the FDX drama. if we're
willing to put out these these glossy
Netflix series, right? It means we've
we've all actually moved on. It's this
cute little part of our history and on
we go. But it's a little bit it's a
little bit triggering to watch.
>> You know, it's it's so triggering. It's
like, let me make a like a really false
Hollywood version of the worst time of
everyone's life that's going to watch
it.
>> That's gonna watch it. That's so true.
It is so true. Yeah. Um Yeah. Yeah. I
mean, I always, we talked about this
before, but uh always every time you say
FTX, I just feel like the the two years
ripped out of my chest that I'll never
get back.
>> How hard did that make your life? like
in in in hindsight like that's a good qu
you I mean now looking back since we can
say that if we're getting the Hollywood
version that it's over how hard did that
make every single meeting you had every
single pitch every single product you
tried to release everything your
business did for those two or three
years
>> it was impossible it was impossible on
two levels I mean it was the largest
financial scam uh you know of all time
um how do you get an if you're an asset
manager serving an institutional
audience
and FTX happened. How do you go to them
and say invest in this industry? Uh like
it's it's it's it's literally
impossible. Um
uh and it was literally impossible. So
and and that happened at the same time
that we had an SEC that was trying to
actively kill our industry. So you had
the government trying to kill our
industry, you had the industry trying to
kill our industry, and you were telling
people this is like an interesting time
to invest because the underlying
technology is sound. It's just a it's
really an incredible thing that crypto
survived and recovered as fast as it
did. Um it still surprises me that we
bounced as fast as we did.
>> Can't wait to see the maid off love
story,
>> right? I mean that's the thing. I think
there is something because it's it's
crypto uh and and and SPF was sort of
strange that makes it okay to do this.
Um but yeah, put it in the maid off
example and and see how people feel
about it with like a little love story.
>> Wall Street. I guess we did get the Wolf
of Wall Street. It wasn't like a massive
fraud against like the world and an
industry, but you know, we do have
movies that in hindsight have glorified
pretty, you know, aggressive financial
crime. That is true.
I just can't get past it that they all
>> and then you get and then you get Hunter
Biden later today.
>> Can't wait.
>> What a day for
>> I What do you ask him? What would you
ask him? Do you Do you want to do it?
>> I don't want to do it. But but but I
would love him to spin the story of how
it turned out well with everyone making
money. Like what is that? What is that
story? What is the story you tell
yourself uh of how that ended up? for
Biden is how he ends up in crypto after
his father's administration was trying
to kill the
>> I mean it seems inevitable
>> ask can I ask him that like why does
your dad hate us
>> yes yeah absolutely
>> does your dad even know that we exist
>> that's that's that's a that's a good
question too um yeah man I think it'll
be great I'll all tune in
>> how's your dad that's gonna I'm gonna
start with how's your dad how's your dad
we you know we're all worried wondering
Matt, thanks for watching that with me,
suffering through that. Um, maybe we
should have a watch party when it
actually comes out where we could
pretend we're not going to watch it, but
then watch it anyways.
>> That sounds right. That sounds right,
>> brutal, man. Thank you, Matt. I'm gonna
stick around. I have a We got to do the
weekly reckoning where I review the
week. So, I'm going to let you go. I
appreciate you getting up early in the
morning as always and for all your
perspective.
>> Yeah, good to see you.
>> Thanks, man.
>> Talk to you later.
Hunter Biden,
he's on the And the thing is I like I
saw him on the calendar and I was like,
didn't like he seems to be on the
circuit,
you know? I don't know how it happened.
I asked my team. I don't know. Hunter
Biden
meth or crack lightning round.
Yeah. What What would you You know what?
Before we move on, that's what my
producer just said. Ask your audience.
What would you guys ask Hunter Biden? $5
to the best answer.
Guys, come on. Hit me with them. I need
you guys in the comments. We're going to
do the the YouTuber thing. Comment in
the comments about your comments that
you're commenting. Crackass.
I don't think I can call him that.
Do you think he's going to watch this
show in the morning and be like, "No."
Uh, ask him about the contrast between
his laptop and Trump Junior is making
billions in government cont. I'm
definitely going to ask him that
The thing is like we just ask him stuff
then he's going to leave.
I was going to say I want to get high
but meth crack is way better.
Does your dad know? Yeah, that's what
does does your dad know about crypto?
Uh, ask him what it was like to sleep
with his brother's wife. That seems bad.
Did he do that?
I'm just clicking stuff. I'm not reading
it first.
>> Unicorn horn 4A.
>> Okay. Well, you guys stopped commenting
where we stopped getting uh Ask him who
his dad's barber is. Yeah, I got to know
that guy. Uh
lol.
Okay. All right. Well, anyways, uh as
you can see here, I'm going to do the
interview. Put it out. Put out. see what
happens. But right now,
we're gonna do this People's Reserve,
guys. You know that every I did it
again. Every
I'm so bad at doing the thing. Uh, every
single Friday, I tell you guys about
People's Reserve, so obviously they're
close friends of mine. I've been working
with them for a very, very long time.
You've seen CJ on the show. Uh, they
have the Bitcoin powered mortgages, but
also the absolutely amazingly incredible
Bitcoin bonds. Uh then we can go here.
Personal Bitcoin bond. You can learn
about it. Earn with people's reserve.
The best of both worlds. 100% downside
protection. Full Bitcoin upside finally.
So basically the bulk of this goes into
US treasuries which are risk-f free as
we all know with a percentage in Bitcoin
so that you capture the upside and are
guaranteed by the math to have 100%
downside protection. So you basically
capture some of the upside of Bitcoin
while still earning on the treasuries.
It's a pretty incredible product that I
highly recommend you taking a look at.
Look, we can do the these are their This
is their amazing calculator. It's sweet.
The bond calculator. I've showed you
this before, but you know, $100,000 at a
5% interest rate over five years with
diamond loyalty. If you assume a 35% K
year, I like to go down to 20. I can't I
just can't mentally assume that Bitcoin
will go up 35% a year. In five years,
you're at 147,000 from 100. You do 10
years, $37,676.
Uh, I think that this is the way that
most people are going to be gaining
Bitcoin exposure into the future. You
can check them out at peopleleserve.com
right there. Bitcoin-bond
calculator. All right. Um, and now that
we have discussed that, uh, we have to
talk more about Hunter Biden and FDX.
Just kidding. So, you know, there's a
thing that we do every single Friday
where I cook through, and I just
accidentally closed one of them, so bear
with me. One of my tabs. Uh, where we
cook through all of the biggest stories
of the week. We like to call it the
weekly reckoning. I'm gonna play the
little thing and we're going to do the
little thing and then we're going to do
the thing and we're going to get it. You
ready?
It is Friday, October 9th, and this is
the weekly reckoning. A very quick
review of all of the meaningful news
from this week. And we have to start
every single week with this beautiful
badass Michael Sailor right here. Back
to buying Bitcoin, baby. Strategy
reports a 21 billion gain on digital
assets in Q3 2026. 21 billion gain. I'm
old enough to remember when people were
saying that Sailor was going to be
forced to sell all of his Bitcoin. He
was going to zero. He was insolvent. He
was bankrupt. And then just months
later, he is dunking on their faces,
legs spread, dangling over their heads
from the rim with a $21 billion gain.
Only bought 334 Bitcoin this week. But
Reed purchased 176 million of STRC,
which is almost back at par. Maybe the
bigger story actually was that Strive
bought 10 times as much Bitcoin as
Strategy this week because Seda, their
comparable product, is trading at par
and they've been able to use that to
continue buying Bitcoin. But the story
here, regardless of what happened in the
past, regardless of the fact that
strategy did sell a lot of Bitcoin at
the bottom only to buy it back $20,000
higher, is that the machine is waking up
and turning back on and that can only be
good news. The second story, joint
venture of OKX and NY parent ICE files
for 24/7 tokenized US stock trading. If
you missed this story, uh then consider
yourself unmissed because I'm telling
you about it right now. This is a 50/50
venture between ICE and OKX to offer
tokenized stocks. Now, most importantly
probably is the fact that there's a
Quomo there. Uh but most importantly is
probably the fact that this is the first
real movement after the SEC's innovation
exemption which laid out the rules for
how tokenized stocks can trade in the
United States. Now that is not a
official rule yet. It's still in the
comment period but we're seeing a lot of
examples of companies and institutions
moving forward as if it will be real and
that's what's happening here. So, this
is basically an exchange called OKX Ice,
which is also a drink that I used to
have in the basement of my fraternity
house in college. We used to kneel and
drink the ice. OKS Ice. Uh, and it's a
joint venture where it will actually be
backed by unis swap liquidity pools from
self-custodied wallets. Crazy that the
intern intercontinental exchange is
participating at this level in
decentralized finance and building this
with OKC. So effectively, even even
Americans hopefully down the road will
be able to trade tokenized versions of
stocks in a decentralized exchange with
a front end from OKX and ICE. Sweet.
Next story. China shuts hundreds of
banks as Beijing moves to shore up its
financial system. Things in China are
not as good as uh you would be led to be
if you listen to China talk about things
in China. They tell you everything's
great. I don't know. I'm not Chinese. Um
but uh clearly there's some rumbles and
bumbles in the Chinese financial system
right now and shutting down a major part
of their financial system to shore that
up seems like bad news that we should
probably be watching. The next story,
SEC approves a 3x fix
Hunter Biden about his 3x fix today. 3x
fix for Bitcoin and Ether traders who
missed the wild swings.
You know what I really missed in crypto?
The volatility.
missed those wild swings. But to be very
clear, these are 3x leverage ETFs, CME,
using options, not the underlying actual
asset. And the leverage resets every
single day. This is important because
there are going to be a lot of dumb
people, not dumb, uneducated,
stupid, dumb, not dumb, stupid people
who see this product and they go, you
know what? I think Bitcoin is going to
go up. I would like to have three times
the exposure to that. But it resets
every day. So let's say you buy a $100
worth of this ETF and it goes up 10% in
a day, you're at 110, right? Say the
next day it goes down 10%. You go from
110, it's now at 99,
right? Uh and you end up actually losing
money massively because you've 3x that
when Bitcoin is flat, right? Right? So
you would get, excuse me, 100, you go to
130 with this. But 130, you take 30%
off. You don't go back to 100. You go
much lower, right? And it's going to
reset every day. There's going to be
massive decay. And you don't want to be
participating in these unless you are
trading daily. This is not an investment
product.
Uh, OKX looks to abstract blockchain
mechanics to bring stable coin balances
to everyday consumers. OKX appears to be
they have an announcement every single
day. I don't do these, my team does. I
just go through the tabs in real time.
OKX appears to be designing products to
keep the blockchain element abstracted
or out of sight for users who simply
want to hold digital dollars and use a
card. So basically, uh there's a huge
yield here and they're building things
that look familiar to other products.
I'll get to a more compelling story
about that in a minute. US bonds sell
off eases yields off highs after strong
10year note auction. Yeah, the news that
I saw actually uh was the opposite that
we had yields at the highest uh in 24
years on the 30. So, that was a very
temporary bounce. Not that exciting.
Yields are rocketing and interest rates
are going up. Robin Hood adds 25 million
of Bitcoin to its balance sheet. Cool.
We have another Bitcoin treasury
company. It's only $25 million, but it's
a great signal from Robin Hood that they
actually want to be personally invested
in the asset class that they've put so
much stock into for their customers. I'm
here to see it because we haven't seen a
Treasury announcement in a very long
time. Bit Bitmine sets 5% ether supply
hard cap as accumulation target nears.
Bitmine is going to stop buying Ethereum
soon. That's the story here. Samsung
integrates USDC to overhaul crossber
remittances for 82 million Galaxy users.
This is the continuation of that story I
told you before. Turns out that the best
way to gain Matt's adoption for crypto
is not to let anybody know that they're
using crypto.
82 million Galaxy users will have USDC
integrated into their wallets for
crossber payments and remittances and it
will look like everything else in their
Samsung wallet. I told you a story about
SoFi recently that their Mastercard
would be all settled on blockchain rails
but behind the surface and you wouldn't
know. The customer would go charge
something they would not know they're
using crypto. The merchant will receive
dollars. They will not use any but all
the plumbing in the background because
it's faster, cheaper and more efficient
will be done by stable coins. That is
exactly what is happening here and it is
on Salana. And the final story in the
weekly recap here, Vitalik, I don't
recommend anyone scramble to move their
funds new wallets today. You'll see that
the Ethereum Foundation's Justin Justin
Drake is his name. Uh said that we have
new FUD. Let's not worry about quantum
because AI is going to be so
mathematically superior before we even
get to quantum that it's going to be
able to crack your keys anyways. Uh
Coinbase pushed back said there's no
reason to believe that the math is at
risk. And then Vitalik came in somewhere
in the middle and said, "Yeah, we should
take this seriously, but I wouldn't go
jumping to a new wallet yet." Like, god
forbid everybody takes their self-
custody and moves to some other
self-custody and we go full cold card
with that new self-custody and it looks
like a disaster. All right, that is all
the stories that I wanted to cover for
this week on the Weekly Reckoning. Got
People's Reserve right back there on a
building. I mean, they're on a building
in New York City. What more do you need
to hear? So am I.
That's all we got for you today. Peter
Schiff Sunday. Should watch it. It's a
really good interview. And then of
course be back on Monday for Macro
Monday.
That's dope.